You saw the SpaceX S1. It's like, oh,
$30 trillion. It's like, what is the
world GDP? 100 trillion.
>> Both Stripe and Open Router really want
lots of new companies in the world. We
don't want everyone to be a part of one
giant company. When the models get more
intelligent, the risk actually will
continue to get higher. And yet, no one
new is taking responsibility. We're
going to slowly realize how good we've
had it with like deterministic code.
remember the days when computers did
exactly what we told them to do.
>> Are we going to prevent the models from
deceiving users during training runs
predictably? Will like a model that's
big enough and powerful enough suddenly
stop deception and stop sandbagging.
Um,
welcome to Asz podcast. We're here with
Amjad of Replet and and Alex of Open
Router. And this is the first podcast
that Alex has done since the
acquisition. So, we're really excited to
have both of you.
>> Mhm. Thank you. Excited to be here.
>> Alex, let's let's start with that
actually if you can briefly um share um
obviously, you know, massive
acquisition. Uh Amjad is an investor.
We're also of course an investor. Um the
biggest shareholder, but yeah, who's
who's counting? Um um Alex, why don't
you give us a little bit of the
backstory like how does acquisition like
that even uh even happen? Like do you
get a DM from Patrick one day? Uh, you
know what? Uh, what what can you share?
>> Hey, how much for an overrouter?
>> I had talked to Will Gabbrick um the
like strike president a long time ago, a
couple years ago when we were doing our
series A and
uh and we just we stayed in touch. we
had like a lot of like Stripe work
streams going on with various teams at
Stripe. Um so there were always sort of
like things that we were doing with
Stripe. um we presented at Stripe
sessions
uh and and and so it always kind of they
always kind of felt close and then yeah
just in in July I believe um they
reached out wanted to chat met met like
both of them in person and
uh and it kind of just progressed from
there fairly quickly. Um they're very
efficient and you know they were very
like founder friendly about the
experience. Um I was really impressed
with the whole thing.
>> Did it did it did you want to sell like
did it even cross your mind before they
shout?
>> No we were not thinking about that at
all. Um I you know did really respect
the company do really respect it today
and you know of possible acquisition
options for us. Um it was I think my top
choice and
uh so it was like an interesting idea.
Uh and you know as we kind of like
fleshed out the reasons why it would
make sense for both companies it got
more and more interesting uh it was
really clear how like aligned they were
with us kind of having autonomy over the
brand and roadmap and product and
keeping open router doing what it's
already doing just much faster with um
much more with like a like a much more
serious gotomarket plan and
um and then you know some better
together stories between the two
products uh and the two the two
companies
and and then culturally there were just
I I think very like in terms of like
mission and values and building like a
neutral trusted platform that businesses
can depend on and scale on top of that's
also really developer friendly with the
best possible developer experience for
you know to encourage new companies to
emerge. um you know that that alignment
was there and there was a bigger picture
kind of alignment too where like you
know both stripe and open router really
want lots of new companies in the world
you know we don't want everyone to be a
part of one giant company we want to
like create really good incentives and
uh and really sort of easy streamlined
workflows for people to start new
companies and grow them successfully and
you know make both lifestyle and
venturebacked businesses on top of
really good like reliable and price
efficient infrastructure and and like a
marketplace that works. Um and you know
I really want that future and Stripe
demonstrated that they've been wanting
it and building towards it for like many
many many years. Um and in many ways
like payments and inference are going to
blend together for companies of the
future.
>> I'm I'm curious uh I understand why
Stripe's incentive
is to have you know much more vibrant
startup ecosystem. I understand the kind
of moral argument and why you would want
that. But why is that good for open
router? Like is your model for open
router is that it's like a network
effects business?
Is it is it like a network?
>> Well, for us, I think the the
there's like a couple different problems
Open Router solves. one is,
you know, allowing you to build a
company that uses AI um or like augments
intelligence with unique data and and
other services uh without model lock in,
without vendor lock in,
>> allowing you to kind of like
be on the PTO frontier continuously as
the ecosystem grows it. And um to do
that it it's a lot of work because
there's all kinds of little lock in that
appears. Um we also
uh you know I I like we want companies
to feel like the the the best way that
they can like add more than just prompts
on top of a single model. there's like a
lot more to building um like unique
intelligence and I think a big component
of that is neurodeiversity. you really
need the the power of multiple models
that are trained in different ways,
including some of your own
>> um to do more than chat GPT or Claude
would on the task if like someone who is
thinking about buying from you as a
potential customer is wondering, well,
what if I just use the model directly?
um like how do you really show that you
are significantly better and able to
build a business that that matters? Um
and I think a lot of it will involve
neurodeiversity and blending like powers
and and good data from multiple models.
Um
another component is is like helping
people get really good cost efficiency.
Like there are a lot of businesses that
just cannot do not emerge until they
become cost effective and like creating
an environment where we can help drive
down costs by building an efficient
market uh is like crucial to making that
happen. Otherwise like you know
why lower my prices as a as a provider?
um we have a captive market and uh and
like you know I think that's like a key
point of marketplaces that was just
totally missing from AI before we showed
up. There was just one player open AI.
It could have been like a uh a very
strange world.
I'm not saying that we did all the work.
Of course not. But like helping people
like choose new models and explore new
models and learn like what makes um
you know a closed source or openw weight
model uh like actually good at your task
involves like seeing what the whole
ecosystem is doing and learning
automatically like LLMs are not things
where you can just enumerate all the
features on a web page. It's impossible.
you you have to see how they're being
used to know what they're good at.
>> So, you started the company three years
ago. I'm I'm curious what is surprised
you the most about sort of the evolution
of open and closed source models to the
present um as it relates to model
performance or just people's uh
perspective on the variety of models
they have available to them.
>> People have been more open-minded than I
thought they would be towards
openweight models. Like typically
there's like a there's a lot of brand
especially an enterprise typically
there's a lot of like brand trust where
like an enterprises you enterprises in
general are like oh I'm you know I don't
really know how to tell the difference
between these things so I'm just going
to like you know buy the one that all
the other credible enterprises are
buying and and there's a lot of like
enterprise
um lock in with like a mentality like
that. Um, and that just didn't happen
that much where they It did happen like
a bit, but uh we saw a lot of
enterprises
uh want to explore new models. It it's
it's simply like it it was m it was very
much good for a marketplace. um
enterprises wanted to diversify outside
of just the proprietary frontier model
labs um both for like cost reasons and
for differentiation reasons. They wanted
to like own their intelligence so they
could um you know I think like one keep
their their talent like have like an
internal AI practice like AI is just
like a huge strategy topic. It's not
like you go to your board and you're
like, "Oh, yeah. Um, you know, we fixed
the AI problem, uh, quarter complete."
Like the your board is like asking you
every month like what, you know, what's
what's next for the AI internal AI team
and all like every single enterprise, it
now has just this, you know, internal AI
team that they're developing where they
they need a strategy behind it.
um it's not just a like, you know, we
check the feature off, we like set up
the database and we're done. Um and so I
think that that uh dynamic has resulted
in just like a desire to explore and
diversify
um and a desire to kind of like figure
out how to reduce costs and figure out
how to do benchmarks for the first time
in the company's life. I have been like
surprised there hasn't been more
benchmarking like more companies
creating more benchmarks. it's starting
to happen and I think like eventually
we'll see a lot more of them um to
demonstrate like oh yeah like this thing
is better than using you know claude
direct but um like I think that's going
to be like a bigger focus for this
internal AI group at every company um
evals and I think like Jud's been doing
that a lot at Replet for example like
you guys have done a lot of cost per
task research
um you guys have And you know, you
you've made like a doom loop rescue.
You've kind of been like experimenting
with new ways of using agents like doom
loop rescue and and uh like helping
bring those to developers. Um
so like more of more of that kind of
research I think is going to pop up
internally everywhere. Um
for all of those reasons. Yeah, I I
think um uh Satcha uh CEO of Microsoft
has been very
uh
very you know preient on this and also
very articulate on um why companies need
to own their intelligence ultimately in
the same way that you know we had dot
companies and then every company became
an internet company like every company
employs people that know how to like
build websites and be on the internet.
Similarly with with software, every
company has software engineers. Every
company needs some AI practice, AI
capability and that will compound over
time the knowledge, the intelligence
inside the company, the the the use case
model fits like which models actually
work for them, how do they save save
money, they need sort of that
independence. The other thing that um I
think Alex Karp of um Palanteer has been
talking about is that there's like a
risk that when you work closely with the
foundation model companies is that
they're going to move into your business
and we've seen that you know with Figma
visavic we've seen that with like now
Harvey and OpenAI and you know it's it's
really hard to partner with them and
because you know they're
they see the world as their potential
market Like I mean when when they talk
to investors they're like you know you
saw the SpaceX S1 it's like oh $30
trillion it's like what is the world GDP
100 trillion and so there is a sense in
which these companies are different than
other generation of companies it's it's
harder to partner with them because
their ambition is is is such that they
want to they want to be they want to
subsume a big part of the economy. Um
and increasingly like what we're
thinking about at replet is kind of in
the similar vein to what Alex have sort
of innovated is uh replet is becoming
more of an independence layer inside
inside enterprises where we create a
layer of interaction between um between
you and the and the models and we get
you the best token at the cheapest
price. uh but also we um we also create
uh an abstraction layer on top of the
cloud as well because you know you
should be able to deploy to AWS and
Azure and you should be able to use data
bricks and snowflake and so on. Um and
so increasingly I think there is not
just with AI with all of technology
there needs to be more platforms that
help companies gain gain independence.
It seems like yeah what Open Router did
for their segment you're you're doing
for other other areas of the business.
>> Yeah,
there was this this kind of reminds me
of this tweet I saw the other day when
somebody was like basically all
companies are building the same thing
now. Everybody's building an agent loop
with like notifications and and context
uh like third party uh connectors and
context management and memory and uh
>> sandbox
>> uh sandboxes
uh you know web you know agentic web
search
>> computer use
>> and an always on agent on top of it and
notifications and it's like this product
is showing up everywhere. Yes.
>> Um, in a way, yeah, it is like
showing up everywhere, but it it also
kind of feels to me like these are just
the new table stakes primitives. It's
kind of like like a 2005 version of that
tweet would be, oh, everybody's building
the same thing. It's like a database, a
users table, a sign-in page, a signup
page, a profile page, a logout page.
like everything's the same. It's like
there's like a lot of differentiation
really. It's just there's like a there's
table stakes needs for AI just like
there are table stakes needs for the
web.
>> Yeah. And and I think um as well like
inside the enterprise
making these products actually do real
work is still unsolved problem like you
can use Muse in your personal life and
connect it to your credit card and bank
accounts and no one's connecting Muse to
their enterprise data or even Grockbot
and things like that. Um I think there's
an even more emphasis on data
sovereignty and and security. So we we
spent the past
you know year almost uh working on
making uh making making replet uh
deployable on your own cloud basically
on prem like bring your own cloud like
two years ago I would have thought I
would never do this uh because you know
it's just like yeah the cloud is the
future like software as service all of
that uh but but now actually we've sort
of like reverted a little bit back to a
world where
companies are a little bit more
protective because there's so many ways
in which data can leak like all these
agents that people are using. I mean
there's all these screenshots on
Twitter. I don't know how true where
Instinct is like or Muse is like mixing
people's data starts to call you by a
different name or something like that.
Uh and so yes, the kind of consumer
stuff is kind of obvious, but on the
enterprise, there's still tremendous
amount of work for the entire industry
to do in order to actually get these
things to be useful and productive at
work.
>> Do you are you doing any like do you
have like a custom personal agent other
than Muse or Instinct that you use for
like work stuff that you've been
building?
Yeah, I mean I I built something on
Replet like a long time ago. Uh I
started as like a sort of a CRM agent
initially. That was the main problem
that I had, but slowly like we added
features to it and it's sort of like
doing more and more things. But what's
what's really interesting is that
the more I connected Replet to my all my
stuff, it sort of like started answering
all the things for me. Um and so
increasingly like the platform itself is
like subsuming these sort of like these
domain specific agents that I built. I
do think that there there is some in
some ways you want something that is
sometimes like focused on one particular
thing and you don't want it to be able
to do everything. On the other hand once
you have your entire company's context
in one place it's really cool to join
across totally different domains. like
when I ask it a question, it can like
look at my sort of personal chat
history, join it across the GitHub repo
across Salesforce. And so it says like
it will link like random things. It's
like, oh, you met this guy like a year
ago at a conference. I see it on your
calendar and by the way, someone else
from their team is in discussion with
your sales team. and it creates all
these different synergies and and when I
go into a meeting I like I you know I
I've connected a lot of different
threads and and I'm I'm make much more
progress on a deal or or something like
that. Uh so so this is where it's sort
of trending now.
>> Well
I I think I I I'm like a little bit I'll
take the counter on that. I think that
the the
worst part about doing crossdain
joins with your personal agent is that
the the more work you give it to do, the
more understanding of what's going on
you're sacrificing.
And yet no one no one knew is taking
responsibility for that sacrifice
understanding. Like agents don't have
any responsibility. you can't like you
like if there's a fixed level of
cortisol that the whole company can
tolerate between everybody
and uh you know you like de
you you uh you like I I want to be like
less stressed about some area if I'm
going to be like sacrificing my
understanding of it
>> someone else needs to take the cortisol
>> but the the agent doesn't
>> like take on any of that responsibility
Um, and like a universal agent that's
doing all things,
you know, I can't adjust how much I'm
sacrificing in all the different things.
It's it like points me a little bit
towards,
you know, maybe like down the road like
the sub agents that people use will be
like very vertically focused. Maybe we
have like a chief of staff type agent
that, you know, coordinates between
them. Um, but I feel like you do need
like vertically focused agents where
you're like, okay, like there this agent
is more responsible psychologically for
these things. Um, and like I want like
quality checks that make sure it's doing
those things correctly. And I it it
doesn't need to focus on anything else.
It just has one focus area. Um, I wonder
if that's gonna like help people like
at least get like a weird loose sense of
responsibility on top of agents.
>> Fascinating. So, so you're saying
general agents create like a tragedy of
commons of sorts?
>> Kind kind of like I have a general agent
that every day um looks for things that
need me and tries to figure out what to
do. And it's just like impossible to
improve this agent.
like I it's it's like every time I try
to make an improvement, I end up like
ignoring its output about a week later.
Um it's it just feels like it doesn't
really care about any of the like
specific things it's diving into. Um,
and uh, like kind of imagine having a
chief of staff where they're very good
at,
you know, like drafting all of your
replies across the whole organization.
Um, and then compare that to something
where you have like 10 chiefs of staff,
each each as competent as that one chief
of staff, but they're all responsible
for like individual sectors of of what
you of what makes up your life. like the
latter I feel like gives you a way of
tuning how much understanding you
sacrifice
>> compared to the the gain you get from
like basically I can like lean in more
to the areas where the agent is failing
for some areas and then have agents with
very good competency like take over my
understanding of other of other parts of
my life.
>> Yeah. Interesting. It's it's sort of
like uh almost rediscovering,
you know, um specialization, right?
What's his name? The like the famous
economist uh Adam um like
>> Adam Smith.
>> Adam Smith like with a pencil kind of
thing where you know that that was like
a huge realization for humanity that
like special specialization
is actually good. The problem is like we
kind of like over specialized as like a
civilization and I think over
specialization
is is um is oppressive in its its own
ways. I mean I think we've
you know um sort of like you know
there's the Marxist theory of alienation
right the the idea is um uh because of
over spec uh uh you know people are
doing just focus on one thing uh they
they do not see the fruits of their
labor they don't actually know what
their impact is on the larger
organization or the product they're
producing and therefore they actually
kind of feel depressed and detached and
and you're kind of acting like a machine
and you're not actually fully fully
human. And so m maybe there's like a bit
of a reaction to that and and and I
think with our agents we're like oh that
there should be like one god god agent
but in fact specialization is actually
like really good for machines and that's
like the the point that you're making
and like humans should be general but
like machines should be ultimately a lot
more specialized.
>> The problem with I think what I'm
describing is that we don't know what
good looks like. There hasn't been a
system of specialized agents that feels
as elegant as like chat GBT or Claude or
Muse. Uh where you're basically just
talking to one thing only.
It it's it's yet to be discovered like
maybe like opening I just launched dots.
Um I think they're kind of like
experimenting in that direction. Gro
like Grockbot I guess kind of counts
that
>> but but they're all they're all very
general. Like I think the idea behind
DOT is that it's like it's like uh it's
like your digital double as at least
that's what I understood it.
>> Well, when I saw Grock bot, I don't know
what what what's going to I don't know
that much about dots yet, but uh they
just came out, but Grock bot when it
first came out, like the first use cases
that I saw people talking about were,
"Oh, wo, I can make two bots. One that
knows my bank account, right,
>> and one that knows my Twitter account."
And the two bots like don't have the
credentials from each other. Yeah.
>> But they can talk to each other if like
they need to get something done. Um
there's no credential sharing though.
And that was like one sort of big unique
thing I saw like a couple time like pop
up a couple times that people seem to
like.
>> But it looks like Muse is but I wasn't
sure.
>> Muse and Instinct are
>> have a much stronger product market fit
than Grockpot. Um, and perhaps
>> seems like that
>> perhaps it is because you don't have to
worry about creating these these
domains, but but I think maybe personal
agents are different than than work
agents. And I think your kind of your
critique of general agents is is more uh
pertaining to to to work and to
enterprise, which I I sort of agree
with. And um you know there's also all
sorts of uh data access considerations.
I think as CEOs we can have general
agents because we have admin access. Uh
but you know you're for individual
employees or certain teams they can't
have like truly general you know fully
contextaw aware agents because there's
there's access control control issues.
So you'll have to kind of work on on
something like specialization.
Ultimately, I also think we need to
figure out what is agent to agent
communication look like. I don't think
there is like good protocols
around that just yet. I I don't think
that agents are trained to handle that
very well. I think we've seen it seems
like the next generation of OpenAI
models are trained
to do agent collaboration because we've
seen it in the hugging face hack where
they start helping each other and sort
of emerge naturally. But there's also
needs to be
some way in which like an agent can't
convince another agent to kind of give
it give it information that it shouldn't
give it give it. like that there's there
needs to be like data um isolation and
and and and and proper ways in which
these agents communicate. You almost
don't want to communicate them fully in
natural language. Maybe that there's
like some other DSL or protocol that
that they need to follow.
>> I really I I I think one of the cool
potential applications of Jev and other
decision models like it is going to be
alignment. you know, checking to see if
a tool call or like an agentto agent,
you know, communication
is aligned because there's just so many
tool calls. Like you really need like a
cheap fast model. Um, if you're going to
block something like that, then uh like
a really really fast decision model that
just classifies and gives feedback on
rejections
um might be like a really good way to
bridge the gap between agents and from
agent to infrastructure too. So I
haven't seen like and we have like a a
little prototype that we're running
internally um at open router but um I
kind of think a good I think it could be
like an interesting alignment
>> using it for policy enforcements.
>> Yeah. Like imagine um uh looking at the
system prompt and the current tool call
being made and be like like you know is
this aligned with the the system prompt
of the original agent and with these
like extra guidelines that maybe we
didn't tell the agent about. For
example, let's say you have a bunch of
agents that are instructed to do um to
like red team the like some some new
product and they cannot should not uh
be able to access the internet. Um and
if they ever do, they should stop right
away. Um but you might not want to like
explain all of that to the agents doing
the red teaming. you might want them to
try to like break out of the sandbox
um and act like bad actors. Like what
would a bad actor do? It wouldn't be
like break out of the sand, you know,
try to like break into this company and
the moment you do stop. Don't do
anything else. Mhm.
>> Um so like having another model more
like you know use for you know building
a neurodeiverse system having another
model like check uh every single tool
call or every single assistant message
to see if it's indeed aligned with
something that wasn't in the system
prompt I think makes sense. Um, and then
having kind of like structural
safeguards too, which is what I think
Nvidia um, just launched with their like
open agent safety. Uh, I think it was
called open shell. Um, like I think
companies are probably going to explore
a combination of those.
>> I I wonder another thing about
specialization and um, sort of what
you're talking about. There's a lot of
talk of recursive self-improvement.
Um there's something I don't think it's
getting a lot of um sort of discussion
which is uh models training their
replacements. It's sort of like you know
you can think of it as a just in time
compiler. So the way just in time
compilers is um you know as you're
executing dynamic code you know the the
the interpreter realizes that there's an
opportunity to optimize it will emit
machine code on the fly and that's a lot
more optimized. So you can imagine
models like general models you're kind
of doing something with Opus or some
some of the Astra or some of the big
models and they realize that the use
case is is limited uh or you prompt them
in some way or some other agent
observing and realizes that use case is
limited and I think you know general
agents have all these flaws that you
just talked about but also there's
there's more potential for them to be
harmful. there's more potential for them
to go off the rails and sort of on the
fly trains a model uh that that could be
it's a replacement but is like a lot
more domain specific uh and therefore it
is cheaper and also um you know less uh
less vulnerable to prompt injections uh
less less less harmful for for you know
because it's less capable um And it's
it's it's almost like a like you know
some system that's training machine
learning models
for specific use cases as it's
monitoring the entire system
>> like would that specific use case be it
involve
um unstructured text generation or very
like structured decision model like
>> it could be unstructured text generation
it could be decision models like even
the case of of of Jav like if you have
if you understand the the inputs ahead
of time. Uh you could potentially like,
you know, take an offtheshelf like Quen
or something like that and like train it
specifically for that policy.
Like for that makes sense to do for cost
reasons.
Um assuming that there aren't
like really like the the model labs, the
frontier model labs might make very
lowcost models um that you can easily
transition to
>> safety. Safety as well, right? Oh yeah,
I see your point.
>> They're so capable. And so I think often
times people are using these big
foundation AGI like models to like it's
like nuking a butterfly, right? It's
like they're very, you know, most of the
times like a lot of the use cases even
unstructured use cases don't need that
capable model.
>> I wish there were more public emails
about this stuff like but a lot of the
eval are private. you just can't see um
whether like when the models get more
intelligent the risk actually
uh will like continue to get higher
because I think there's also an argument
to be made that alignment will get
better and the models will like start to
you know avoid going off and you know
hacking on their own um as we as they
get smarter and better at alignment
especially when it comes to agentto
agent coordination like the the this is
something Noam Brown um said on a
podcast recently like as the agents have
gotten smarter, they've gotten just
better at coordinating. Um there uh
there's they're there's still like and
and you know it's unclear if they're
going to like be harder to align than
humans when they're when we get more and
more of them. But if we can figure that
problem out um then a smaller model
like will it be harder to align?
>> So so Eric asked earlier is is that do I
think it's true that smarter models are
are more aligned naturally or they're
easier to to align? Well, I if you think
back to the original sort of like
rationalist less wrong arguments for AI
safety, there is this thing called the
orthogonality thesis. The idea is that
intelligence is orthogonal to ethics or
morality or you know so on. Um I don't
believe that's entirely true with with
humans. I think people who are generally
like more intelligent kind of more more
educated tend to tend to not always tend
to you be more considerate of animals
for example um but uh but but in in in
in machines
uh I I think it could go the the other
way because you know there's been quite
a bit of studies on on on RL Well,
showing like, you know, how reward
hacking and deception they just like get
better at it. And like the evals could
be
could be deceiving because uh the model
could be smart enough to to to
know that it's getting evaled.
I mean, we already know this. It's been
shown that if you do a lot of monitoring
of chain of thought, they start lying in
their chain of thoughts.
Um, and so you add pressure almost on
the chain of thought and that that kind
of creates and and I think at some point
for you to do proper alignment evals,
you need to run it for like months,
>> right? You need to run this thing for
months on a like a really large, you
know, goal or task in order for for it
to to truly kind of figure out whether
it's aligned or or or not.
Yeah. I I I always struggle with this
word alignment. It just feels like
wrong for so many reasons. It's it's
sort of like vague and and uh sort of
like aligned to what whose values and
and so it just doesn't make the
conversation easier. I think in this
case I'm talking especially about
deception like the model is actually
deceiving its user. I mean I I mean
maybe this kind of reduces to like are
we going to solve the line, you know,
are we going to prevent the models from
deceiving users during training runs
predictably with like you know better
like like will will like a model that's
big enough and powerful enough suddenly
stop deception and stop sandbagging?
Um
and nobody knows the answer to that yet.
So like at the point when that does you
if that ever does happen though we might
see kind of an interesting
pressure for organizations to go towards
the frontier like
>> oh interesting
>> you know all uh to have no you know
basically no risk or or significantly
less um
>> would they would they be willing to pay
10x to to get that that much? I mean, it
probably depends on the like types of
tasks they're trying to do.
>> Like, you know, some just have way lower
risk than others. Um, writing code
uh that or doing like security research
is the highest risk type of task today.
And so you probably spend 10x to get a
fully aligned model that can also find
all the bugs or fully like
anti-deceptive model that can also find
all the bugs. One of the coolest things
about decision models is that you fully
control the structured output and and
generally with structured output models
in general like the the room for
misbehavior is so much lower. you just
have like defined tasks and only
machines are like dealing with the
outputs and it's not writing code um
that it can execute the those tasks feel
like probably under represented in the
ones that people talk about and in the
things that enterprises are dealing
with. Um so I I expect like enterprises
to get a lot more interested in them.
>> Yeah. I I feel like we're going to
slowly
realize
how good we've had we've had it with
like deterministic code. We're like, "Oh
my god, remember the days when when
computers did exactly what we told them
to do?" And I think like things like Jev
I think hint at
like more more of a need for you know
not only specialized models but models
whose outwood domain
is is more controllable and maybe you
could do maybe you could do a lot more
than than we thought you you'd need um
you know by using like a bunch of
specialized models specialized output
models.
>> Have you guys done any workloads
internally with it?
>> You know, I've been training a lot of
small models. Uh, I mean, I said this
glip thing when it first came out
because I I I was like sort of I gave
this hacker news comment like comment
which I felt disgusted with myself
afterwards. But I I've been taking a lot
of like Quen 8B and like um and like
asking honestly like asking you know
Fable and Opus and Austra to train a
model. For example, I trained a cost
estimator model uh internally so that
when you put it in a prompt in replet,
we know exactly how much it it will
cost. And it basically emits a you know
probability distribution over multiple
buckets like if it is between five and
$10 bucket A bucket B between you know
10 and $20 and like so I'm used to the
training these classifiers
by you know giving it different enums
essentially and and looking at the log
props per enum.
>> I've been doing it for for a couple of
years. I trained a chatbot to play by
just doing that. So I I'm I'm already
sort of pilled on like sort of decision
models and specialized models. So it
wasn't that big moment for me. But I
understand that like a found like a true
foundation model that's fully promptable
uh is like is like amazing user exper
amazing developer experience and you can
like do a bunch of stuff with it without
training a model from scratch. But if
you have a data, if you work at a place
where you you have the data, we have so
much data at Replet. Like I ended up
training a lot of specialized
classification models pretty easily.
>> Yeah. Like I definitely it it also feels
like less model debt. Like something
that I I still hear from companies is
that they're like worried about
fine-tuning models for like unstructured
outputs because you're just like always
you got to redo it again in like two
months and everybody just feels the
model the weight of the model debt. But
like a very bespoke classifier that's
trained with like proprietary data,
>> you just I I feel like people won't
think it's behind constantly and it
might just like last longer.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
it's just you you you don't have to
worry about its ability to speak a new
language or write Rust or, you know, do
anything that like the the LLMs are
being like evaluated on. You know the
use cases so you can like build it more.
And I I I it seems like an easy thing
for enterprises to build themselves and
uh and it and actually like not regret.
>> Yeah. Speaking of Rust, actually like a
good analogy is when the world got super
excited about dynam dynamic languages.
Um like if you think back to the 90s,
everyone was writing in Java and C++
things like that. And then like Python,
JavaScript, Ruby just like took over the
internet and everyone was like ah this
is how you build startups really
quickly. this is and you built Stripe, a
financial organization on Ruby. I was
like, how crazy is that? And and we
built Facebook, you know, using using
PHP. And then everyone was like, oh
Like we're running into all these
really bad bugs. It's like freaking
slow. Uh so like let's go in and add
types. Okay, let's add a JIT compiler.
Let's And you end up sort of reinventing
everything. And then Rust came out. I
was like, "Okay, I guess we can use Rust
for for a lot of things we would
otherwise be using JavaScript and
Python." And my prediction is that the
same cycle will happen here where we're
using these AGI like models for all
these different use cases and then
everyone's going to wake up and be like,
"Oh my god, this is like so wasteful, so
risky for no reason." Um, and and
there's it's got to be so much easier.
We're actually adding that capability on
Replet, but I think it's going to be
everywhere. it's it's going to be so
much easier to like to go on a site like
upload a CSV file and get a special
model that does one thing. Uh and um you
know that that goes back to your thesis
about open router this like neuro
neurodeiversity which I like really
fundamentally believe in a lot more and
Eric and I had like discussions a lot
about like AGI and whether we we're
truly on a path to AGI or whether it's
even desirable to to to get there. And I
think the future is is a lot more
diversity
>> outside of code review, which was like I
think the first time I saw people get
really serious about using like
different model families to doublech
checkck the results of their main model.
um the uh these like fusion models like
I I like the research has been getting
has been like kind of slow for years on
like doing mixture of of models and
composite models,
but like things have been speeding up
from my like view of the research and
and I mean now we see like a bunch of AI
agent labs
Um like we launched a fusion uh tool, a
fusion model and Cognition launched one
and like they do reduce cost um follow
and and allow like you know a wider
breadth of ideas to be searched like our
initial launch was focused on deep
research. The thinking is that like if
all these model apps are training on
different sources of data like why not
pull from all of them and uh and this
like resulted in basically fable level
quality at 2x lower cost.
>> We just published results actually just
just today about about that. We we we
showed like a deep sweethe
through through combination different
things including the harness but but
also you might think of it as a fusion
type thing
um where it's like um you know frontier
level at like 40 to 50% of the cost
>> and uh which models does it use? I think
it's it changes over time, but one thing
that has been interesting is I think
OpenAI
added this feature that allows you to
save um the computation uh like uh
across different model families. So you
can like also across different um effort
levels.
Mhm.
>> So, uh, like you wouldn't do
you wouldn't miss the cash if you change
the effort. Don't quote me on this. I
think it's also across different models,
which is hard to fathom how. I might be
wrong though, but I I need to double
check that. But I think, you know,
staying within the OpenAI family has
like added a lot of efficiencies, but in
the past we've done it with other with
other with other models as well because
cache is is like one of the big like
being cash aware is like one of the
biggest things when you're designing
fusion models, routers, um sort of
escalation models. Alex, this has been a
great conversation. Thank you. podcast.